Finding Aid for Commercial catalog collection, 1870s-2000s
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Commercial catalog collection 1870s-2000s
Bentley Historical Library.
FB 2; C357; M678
527 items
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection of Michigan-based commercial trade catalogs was accumulated from different sources.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Bentley Historical Library early in its history began developing a collection of commercial trade catalogs. These catalogs have been drawn together from many sources to aid researchers interested in a specific industry or product.
This collection of Michigan-based trade catalogs dates from the 1870s and continues to the present. The collection is arranged alphabetically by broad product classification, for example agricultural machinery, furniture, etc. Within each category, the catalogs have been arranged alphabetically by the name of the company, and then chronologically. The researcher should note that there is a separate finding aid for the library's collection of commercial catalogs for automobiles and motor trucks.
Genre Terms:
Trade catalogs--Michigan.
- Agricultural Machinery
  - Advance Thresher Co., Battle Creek, Mich (Box 1)
    - 1898, Catalog for 1898, (Advance threshing machinery) (Box 1)
    - 1905, Catalog of Advance threshing machinery (Box 1)
  - Advance-Rumely Thresher Co., LaPorte, Ind
    - 1917, Advance-Rumely threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - 1920, Catalog of Advance-Rumely Threshing Machinery (oil pull tractors, ideal separators, traction engines, etc.) (Box 1)
    - 1921, The right foundation for power farming (Box 1)
    - 1924, Advance-Rumely power farming machinery (includes farm trucks) (Box 1)
    - 1926, How a good thresher is built (general line of farm machinery) (Box 1)
    - 1926, Advance-Rumely Combine harvesters (Prairie type) (Box 1)
    - 1928, Advance-Rumely steel threshers (Box 1)
    - 1928, Repair parts price list for the Advance-Rumely No. 2 Combine Harvester Prairie Type (Catalog no. 28) (Box 1)
    - 1930, Advance-Rumely Ideal all-steel separators (Box 1)
    - 1931, U.S. price list, and telegraphic cipher (Box 1)
    - circa 1923, Instructions for operating the Rumely Ideal Separator (instruction booklet no. 23) (Box 1)
    - circa 1924, Instructions for operating the Advance-Rumely Clover and Alfalfa Hullers (Inst. booklet no. 24) (Box 1)
    - circa 1928, Advance-Rumely steel separators (Box 1)
    - circa 1930, Advance-Rumely combine-harvesters (Hillside type) (Box 1)
    - circa 1930, Advance-Rumely combine harvesters (Prairie type) (Box 1)
    - circa 1930, Advance-Rumely steel threshers (Box 1)
  - Allis-Chalmers Rumely, Milwaukee, Wis
    - 1933, A-C-R Combine-harvesters (Prairie type) (Box 1)
    - circa 1935, Operating instructions, special attachments, and repair parts book for Allis-Chalmers Model 40 All-Crop harvester (Box 1)
  - American Harrow Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Repair catalog: Detroit-American tongueless disc harrow (Montgomery Ward) 1917 (Box 1)
  - Aspinwall Manufacturing Co., Jackson, Mich
    - Aspinwall potato machinery. circa 1903 (Box 1)
    - Catalog of Aspinwall Potatoe Machinery 1905 (Box 1)
  - Aultman & Miller Co., Akron, Ohio
    - Advertising calendar for the year 1886 (Box 1)
  - Bolinder-Munktell, Eskilstuna, Sweden
    - Munktells 6' skordetroska circa 1946 (Box 1)
    - Munktells skordetroska, modell MST4 Undated (Box 1)
  - Cayuga Chief Manufacturing Co., Auburn, N.Y
    - Cayuga Chief Mower and Reaper. 1872 (Box 1)
  - Deere & Co., Moline, Ill
    - John Deere skordetroska nr 12A (Swedish) circa 1948 (Box 1)
  - Ford Motor Co., Dearborn, Mich
    - 1920, Fordson tractor manual (Box 1)
  - Furst and Bradley Manufacturing Co., Galesburg, Mich
    - Catalog of plows, riding and walking cultivators, etc. 1877 (Box 1)
    - Catalog of plows, riding and walking cultivators, etc. 1880 (Box 1)
      (IMPERFECT: pages 1-100 missing)
  - McCormick Harvesting Machine Co., Chicago, Ill
    - 1888, Directions for setting up and operating the McCormick steel harvester and binder, with square pipe frame (Box 1)
    - Undated, Directions for setting up and operating the McCormick Corn Binder (Box 1)
    - Undated, leaf of catalog-The McCormick New 4 Mower and the McCormick Light Hand Binder (Box 1)
  - Nichols & Shepard Co., Battle Creek, Mich
    - 1871, Tenth annual "Vibrator" Thresher Catalog (Box 1)
    - 1885, Factory price list for "Vibrator" threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - 1885, Telegraphic cipher code book (Box 1)
    - 1903, Catalog of threshing machinery (threshers, engines, horse powers, stackers, feeders, weighters, etc.) (Box 1)
    - 1904, Catalog of threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - 1921, Catalog of "Red River" threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - 1922, Catalog of "Red River" threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - 1923, Catalog of oil-gas tractors (Box 1)
    - 1923, Catalog of steam traction engines (Box 1)
    - 1924, Catalog of "Red River" threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - circa 1886, Catalog for clover-hulling attachment to the Vibrator threshing machines (Box 1)
    - circa 1895, Vibrator threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - circa 1920, Catalog of "Red River" threshing machinery (Box 1)
    - circa 1920, Directions for operating oil-gas engines (Box 1)
    - circa 1906, Catalogue of threshing machinery (Box 1)
  - Rumely Products Co., LaPorte, Ind
    - Steam engine specifications for the advance line and Gaar-Scott line coal and wood burners and steam burners 1913 (Box 1)
  - S. T. Bryan and Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Burdick's national hay, straw & stalk cutters 1869 (Box 1)
  - Nichols & Shepard Co., Battle Creek, Mich (Box 2)
    - 1928, Catalog of Nichols-Shepard combines (Box 2)
    - 1928, Factory parts price list for 1928 (Box 2)
    - 1931, Parts price list for Model C, D, and E, combines (Box 2)
    - 1931, Parts price list for the 20x30 combine (Box 2)
    - circa 1926, How a good thresher is built (Box 2)
  - Oliver Corporation, Battle Creek, Mich
    - 1933, List of U.S. Branches, sub-branches and major transfer stock points (Box 2)
    - 1935, Catalog for the Oliver Grain Master Combine (model 6-6ft. combine) (Box 2)
    - 1935, Catalog for the Oliver Nichols & Shepard Combine (Box 2)
    - 1935, Instruction manual for Oliver Grain Master Combine (Box 2)
    - 1935, Oliver Heavy Line Price List, effective June 1, 1935 (Box 2)
    - 1938, Catalog for the Oliver Grain Master Combine (model 10--8, 10, and 12 foot combines) (Box 2)
    - 1938, Catalog for the Oliver Grain Master Combine (Model 6--6 foot combine) (Box 2)
    - 1938, Catalog for the Oliver Grain Master Combine Model 6 (Operator's Manual) (Box 2)
    - 1938, Catalog for the Red River Special Threshing Machinery (Box 2)
    - 1941, Catalog for the Oliver Grain Master Combine (Model 20--8 foot combine) (Box 2)
    - 1946, Catalog for the Oliver Grain Master Combine (all models) (Box 2)
    - 1947, Catalog for the Oliver Grain Master Combine (Model 15) (Box 2)
    - 1947/1948 Oliver Shield (Co. periodical) for September-October, 1947-October-November 1948 (Box 2)
    - 1948, Catalog for the Oliver Corn Master Corn Picker (Model 5) (Box 2)
    - 1948, Catalog for the Oliver Tractor (Models A & B) (Box 2)
    - 1952, Parts Price List for the Oliver Mounted Corn Picker (Model 4) (Box 2)
    - 1953, Catalog for the Oliver 6 foot Combine (Model 15) (Box 2)
    - 1953, Catalog for the Oliver Electric Farm Wagons (Box 2)
    - 1954, Parts Price List for the Oliver Pick Up Baler (Model 50) (Box 2)
    - 1954, Setting up and operating instructions for the Oliver Baler (Model 50) (Box 2)
    - 1954, Setting up and operating instructions for the Oliver Mower (Model 27) (Box 2)
    - 1955, Catalog for the Oliver 5, 6 Plow Super 99 GM Diesel (Box 2)
    - 1955, Catalog for the Oliver 7-foot Combine (Model 18) (Box 2)
    - 1955, Catalog for the Oliver One-Row Pull-Type Corn Picker (Model 5) (Box 2)
    - 1955, Catalog for the Oliver Single-Row Semimounted Corn Picker (Model 6) (Box 2)
    - 1955, Catalog for the Oliver Two-Row Mounted Corn Picker (Model 4) (Box 2)
    - 1955, Catalog for the Oliver Two-Row Pull-Type Corn Picker (Model 3) (Box 2)
    - 1955, Parts Price List for the Oliver Mower (Model 24) (Box 2)
    - 1955, Setting up and operating instructions for the Oliver Mower (Model 24) (Box 2)
    - 1957, Leaflet advertising the Oliver Self-Propelled Harvester (Model 40) (Box 2)
    - 1958, Catalog for the Oliver Standard "88" Tractor (4-page leaflet) (Box 2)
    - 1958, Leaflet adv. the New Oliver 2-3 Plow 550 Tractor (Box 2)
    - 1958, Leaflet adv. the New Oliver 3-4 Plow 770/880 4-5 Plow (Box 2)
    - 1958, Leaflet adv. the Oliver Rice Special Harvester(self propelled Model 40) (Box 2)
    - 1958, Leaflet adv. the Oliver Row Crop "66" Tractor (Box 2)
    - 1958, Leaflet adv. the Oliver Row Crop "77" Tractor (Box 2)
    - 1958, Leaflet adv. the Oliver Self-Propelled Combine (Model 35, 40) (Box 2)
    - 1958, Parts Price List for the Oliver Model 60 Pick-Up Baler (Box 2)
    - 1958, Parts Price List for the Oliver Model 60-T Pick-Up Baler (Box 2)
    - 1958, Parts Price List for the Oliver Model 60-W Pick-Up Baler (Box 2)
    - 1958, Setting up and operating instructions for the Oliver Model 60-W Pick-Up Baler (Box 2)
    - Swedish export catalogs 1937, Oliver Traktorer (Tractor Models 25, 35, 45) (Box 2)
    - Swedish export catalogs- 1948 Katalog NR40 a muskiner och redskap for lantbruk och industri (general line of tractors and harvesting machinery) (Box 2)
    - Undated, Oliver 35 Tractor, 1 folders (Box 2)
    - Undated, Oliver Model 20 Tractor, 1 folders (Box 2)
    - Undated, Oliver Model 25 Tractor, 1 folders (Box 2)
    - Undated, Operating instructions for the Model 33 self-propelled combine (Box 2)
    - Undated, Operating instructions for the Oliver Grain Master Self-propelled Combine (Model 33) (Box 2)
    - Undated, Setting up instructions for the assembly of the Model 33 self-propelled combine. (Form S4-3-L1) (Box 2)
    - Undated, Setting up instructions for the assembly of the Model 33 self-propelled combine. (Form S4-3-L23) (Box 2)
  - Parks Manufacturing Co., Mecosta, Mich
    - 1888, illustrated catalog and price list. Potatoe bug and plant sprinkler, and "King of the Dairy" milk can (Box 2)
    - King of the Dairy cold air milk can. undated (Box 2)
  - D. C. & H. C. Reed & Co., Kalamazoo, Mich (Box 3)
    - Folder adv. seeders, harrows & cultivators circa 1886 (Box 3)
  - Port Huron Engine & Thresher Co., Port Huron, Mich
    - Catalog No. 65 (1916) of general line of threshing machines, traction engines, corn shellers, saw mills, road building machinery, etc. 1916 (Box 3)
    - Catalog of the general purpose Port Huron lines (traction engines, threshing machinery, corn shellers, hay presses, saw mills, etc.) 1913 (Box 3)
    - The only general purpose engine circa 1900 (Box 3)
  - Rumely Products Co., LaPorte, Ind
    - 1909, Rumely catalog, pp. 21-33 only (Box 3)
    - 1911, Rumely catalog, pp. 33-54 only (Box 3)
    - 1913, Steam engine specifications (Box 3)
    - 1915, Catalog of power farming machinery (Box 3)
    - 1916, Catalog of Rumely threshing machinery (Box 3)
- Architecture--Designs and Plans
  - Active Homes Corporation, Marlette, Mich
    - Better living planner. 1977 (Box 3)
  - Educator Sales, Inc., Jackson, Mich
    - Relocatable classrooms. circa 1968 (Box 3)
  - Hopkins and Davis, architects, Bay City, Mich
    - A collection of practical and economical house and cottage designs [$500 to $12,000] for 1905 (Box 3)
  - Hopkins, D. S., architect, Grand Rapids, Mich
    - House and cottage designs, containing 16 designs, costing from $3,300 to $10,000 [book no. 9, for 1897] (Box 3)
    - House and cottage designs, containing 43 designs, costing from $1,200 to $6,100 [book no. 12, 2nd ed., for 1899] (Box 3)
    - House and cottage designs...costing from $1,600 to $2,500 [book no. 7, 5th ed. circa 1895] (Box 3)
    - Houses and cottages, containing 54 designs, costing from $2,600 to $3,500 [book no. 8 circa 1895] (Box 3)
  - International Mill & Timber Co., Bay City, Mich
    - The famous fifty: Sterling system-built homes. 1915 (Box 3)
  - Miller Homes, inc., Detroit, Mich
    - Facts about your new home. 1948 (Box 3)
  - National Log Construction Co., Grayling, Mich
    - Plan portfolio of rustic log cabins 1939 (Box 3)
    - Presenting air-lock log cabins 1939 (Box 3)
  - Otsego Log Cabin Co., Gaylord, Mich
    - The cabin home you can afford to own. circa 1945 (Box 3)
  - Paterson Brothers and Co., (Realtors), Detroit, Mich
    - Number 491 Keelson Drive, Detroit, Michigan. Undated, (Spanish-Style house. Pictures of unfurnished interiors.) (Box 3)
  - Riverbend Timber Framing, Blissfield, Mich
    - Planning the timber frame home: a design primer. 10th ed. 1997 (Box 3)
  - Riverside Lumber Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Better homes; a select collection of practical designs for moderately priced homes, ed. & pub. by the Michigan Retail Lumber Dealers Assn. 1921 (Box 3)
  - Von Holst, H. V. [architect] Chicago, Ill
    - Modern American homes [designs] for 1913 circa 1912 (Box 3)
  - Aladdin Co., Bay City, Mich (Box 4)
    - Advance messenger of Aladdin Undated (Box 4)
    - Aladdin homes [Catalog 44 1931] (Box 4)
    - Aladdin Readi-cut homes [Catalog 55 1950] (Box 4)
    - Aladdin readi-cut homes, Catalog 48. 1936 (Box 4)
    - Catalog of Aladdin homes [23d annual catalog 1929] (Box 4)
    - Catalog of Aladdin homes [Catalog 29 for 1917] (Box 4)
    - Catalog of Aladdin homes [Catalog 30, for 1918] (Box 4)
    - Catalog of Aladdin homes [Catalog 32, 2nd ed. 1920] (Box 4)
    - Four Special Aladdins for 1924 (Box 4)
    - New look in homes for 1950 (Box 4)
  - Lewis Manufacturing Co., Bay City, Mich (Box 5)
    - Lewis homes: homes of character. 1920 (Box 5)
    - Lewis homes: homes of character. 1922 (Box 5)
    - Lewis homes: homes of character. 1924 (Box 5)
    - Liberty homes. 1937 (Box 5)
    - Liberty homes. circa 1940 (Box 5)
    - Liberty ready-cut homes. circa 1952 (Box 5)
    - Liberty ready-cut homes. circa 1953 (Box 5)
    - New Liberty homes. circa 1938 (Box 5)
- Carriages and Carts (Box 6)
  - Anderson Carriage Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue. 1901 (Box 6)
  - Brewster, E. E., Holly, Mich
    - Three broadsides advertising safety rein holder circa 1887 (Box 6)
  - Capital Wagon Co., Lansing, Mich
    - Folder advertising the "Capital" farm and road wagons circa 1885 (Box 6)
  - Collins Manufacturing Co., Jackson, Mich
    - Catalogue of the Collins road and speed cart, Himes' wagon and pack surveys, etc. circa 1890 (Box 6)
  - Deal, Jacob J., Jonesville, Mich
    - Catalogue of carriages, buggies, phaetons, and cutters circa 1879 (Box 6)
  - Detroit Carriage Manufacturing Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue. 1902 (Box 6)
  - Farmers' Handy Wagon Co., Saginaw, Mich
    - Catalogue of Farmers' handy wagons [cat. 12 circa 1900 (Box 6)
    - Catalogue of Farmers' handy wagons [cat. 8 circa 1896 (Box 6)
    - Catalogue of the Farmers' handy wagon and city truck circa 1895 (Box 6)
  - Flint Wagon Works, Flint, Mich
    - Farm wagon catalog No. 21 Undated (Box 6)
    - New line of road wagons and road carts Undated (Box 6)
  - Grand Rapids Engraving Co., Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Testimonial book displaying engravings of carriages made for several carriage companies 1902 (Box 6)
  - Harrison Wagon Works, Grand Rapids, Mich
    - Catalogue [and advertising calendar] of the Harrison Farm Wagon circa 1891 (Box 6)
  - Kalamazoo Cart Co., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Color folder advertising the "Acme" road breaking and speeding cart circa 1888 (Box 6)
  - Lansing Wagon Works, Lansing, Mich
    - Catalog No. 24 1903 (Box 6)
    - Catalog No. 25 1903 (Box 6)
  - Michigan Buggy Co., Kalamazoo, Mich
    - Leaflet advertising road carts circa 1875 (Box 6)
  - Pontiac Buggy Co., Pontiac, Mich
    - Vehicles and sleighs 1905 (Box 6)
  - Tiffany Brothers, Jonesville, Mich
    - Catalogue of carriages and platform spring wagons circa 1884 (Box 6)
    - Catalogue of carriages, phaetons, platform spring wagons, etc. circa 1881 (Box 6)
  - Unknown Co., Grand Rapids?, Grand Rapids?, Mich
    - Catalog of wagons and buggies (Box 6)
      (t.p., some pages missing)
- Bicycles (Box 7)
  - National Cycle Manufacturing Co., Bay City, Mich
    - The '96 flyer of the National bicycle. circa 1896 (Box 7)
  - Overman Wheel Co., Chicopee, Mass
    - Victor bicycles. 1896 (Box 7)
- Boats, Marine Hardware, and Supplies
  - Ann Arbor Boat Co., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Launches, row boats, canoes: let us build them right for you. 1908 (Box 7)
  - Brooks Boat Manufacturing Co., Saginaw, Mich
    - Catalogue no. 14. 1906 (Box 7)
  - Chris-Craft Corp., Algonac, Mich
    - Chris-Craft runabouts, utility boats, express cruisers, cruisers, motor yachts. circa 1951 (Box 7)
    - They're terrific! Try 'em! Troll 'em! Clock 'em! 5 1/2 and 10 h.p. Chris-Craft outboard motors. circa 1951 (Box 7)
  - Gray Motor Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Boat builders catalog. 3d ed. Catalog 14. circa 1920s (Box 7)
    - Gray marine motors. Catalog 30. circa 1920s (Box 7)
  - Racine Boat Manufacturing Co., Muskegon, Mich
    - The blue book of motor boats. Undated (Box 7)
  - Truscott Boat Manufacturing Co., St. Joseph, Mich
    - Twenty-two and one-half foot Truscott fast family runabout. Undated (Box 7)
  - Waterman Marine Motor Co., Detroit, Mich
    - We build engines for all kinds of boats. circa 1908 (Box 7)
- Chemicals
  - Diamond Crystal Salt Co., Saint Clair, Mich
    - Salt in industry. 1957 (Box 7)
    - Story of Diamond Crystal Salt. circa 1940s (Box 7)
  - Dow Chemical Co., Midland, Mich
    - Agricultural chemical research. circa 1960s (Box 7)
    - Chemical thinning of fruit circa 1949 (Box 7)
    - Dow contact herbicide circa 1946 (Box 7)
    - Dow phenothiazine circa 1947 (Box 7)
    - Dow sprout inhibitor dust circa 1948 (Box 7)
    - Dow sprout inhibitor circa 1947 (Box 7)
    - Dowspray 66 improved circa 1948 (Box 7)
    - Dowzene 34, Dowzene DHC circa 1961 (Box 7)
    - Dursban insecticide technical information circa 1967 (Box 7)
    - How to cure concrete with Dowflake circa 1936 (Box 7)
    - Life insurance for homes circa 1949 (Box 7)
    - Life insurance for lumber circa 1948 (Box 7)
    - Penta-chlorophenol for industry circa 1947 (Box 7)
    - Penta-chlorophenol on the farm circa 1948 (Box 7)
    - Pentachlorophenol an ideal wood preservative circa 1945 (Box 7)
    - Pentachlorophenol-treated wood means life insurance for your home circa 1949 (Box 7)
    - Phenol properties and handling circa 1949 (Box 7)
    - Post preservation pays circa 1949 (Box 7)
    - Saran Wrap today. circa 1950s (Box 7)
    - Stop fence post rot with Dow wood preservative containing pentachlorophenol circa 1948 (Box 7)
    - Stop fence post rot with Dow wood preservative-a pentachlorophenol concentrate circa 1949 (Box 7)
    - Stop fence post rot with Dow wood preservative-a pentachlorophenol concentrate circa 1950 (Box 7)
    - Versene CA food grade circa 1960 (Box 7)
  - J. B. Ford Co., Wyandotte, Mich
    - Questions and answers for dry cleaners on solvent clarification. circa 1920s (Box 7)
  - Morton Salt Co., Chicago, Ill
    - History of salt. circa 1920s (Box 7)
      [includes pictures of Mich. plants]
  - Neogen Corporation, Lansing, Mich
    - Annual report. 1994 (Box 7)
    - Diagnostics catalog. circa 1994 (Box 7)
  - Solvay Process Co., Syracuse, N.Y
    - Solvay alkali: its various forms & uses.. 1916 (Box 7)
      [includes pictures of Detroit plant]
  - Wyandotte Chemicals Corporation, Wyandotte, Mich
    - Modern commercial dishwashing. circa 1950 (Box 7)
    - Wyandotte Kreelon. circa 1950s (Box 7)
    - Wyandotte sanifacts. no. 4 1959; no. 3, 1965 (Box 7)
    - Wyandotte wigwam. October 1950 (Box 7)
- Clocks and Watches (Box 8)
  - Colonial Manufacturing Co., Zeeland, Mich
    - A book of information for retail salesman circa 1915 (Box 8)
    - Colonial Clocks catalog no. 14. circa 1910s (Box 8)
    - For all time. 1927 (Box 8)
  - Sligh Furniture Co., Holland, Mich
    - Trend Clocks 1978/79 (Box 8)
- Clothing and Dress
  - Allan Sheldon and Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Price list of staple and fancy dry goods, cloths, hoisery, gloves, etc (Box 8)
  - Bortree Corset Co., Jackson, Mich
    - Catalogue of "Duplex" corsets circa 1901 (Box 8)
  - Charles A. Eaton Co., Brockton, Mass
    - Catalogue of men's shoes for 1904-1905 (Box 8)
  - Chris Triola Designs, Lansing, Mich
    - Chris Triola. circa 1990s (Box 8)
  - Clark, H. W., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - English custom riding boots circa 1934 (Box 8)
  - Consumers Clothing Co., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Catalogue of men's suits and overcoats, for autumn and winter 1908-1909 (Box 8)
  - Decker Bros., Battle Creek, Mich
    - Catalogue of ladies' and misses' furnishing goods and infants' wardrobes. [not illustrated] 1882-1883 (Box 8)
    - Demorest's Illustrated Monthly January, July, September, 1865, May 1866 (Box 8)
  - Hall, Marvin E., Hillsdale, Mich
    - Catalogue of "Sons of Veterans" and military goods, silk and bunting flags, swords, uniforms, etc. [List no. 7 circa 1870] (Box 8)
  - Hammond and Judd, Pontiac, Mich
    - Style book of men's and young men's clothing from Hart, Schaffner, and Marx, Fall-Winter 1912-1913 (Box 8)
    - Style book of men's clothing from Hart, Schaffner and Marx, Spring-Summer 1911 (Box 8)
    - Style book of men's clothing from Hart, Schaffner and Marx, Spring-Winter 1910 (Box 8)
    - Style book of men's clothing from Hart, Schaffner, and Marx, Fall-Winter 1911-1912 (Box 8)
  - Hay and Todd Manufacturing Co., Ypsilanti, Mich
    - Sample fabric card: Ypsilanti health underwear for ladies circa 1890 (Box 8)
  - Lamb Knit Goods Co., Colon, Mich
    - Season of 1895. Description and price list of plain and fancy knit gloves and mittens. Specialties in silks and fine Australian wools. 1895 (Box 8)
  - Mabley & Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Special to non-residents [clothing, shoes] undated (Box 8)
  - Mack & Co., Ann Arbor, Mich
    - Fashions and home December, 1926; March 1927; December 1928-January 1929; February-March, 1928, June-July 1928, October-November 1928 (Box 8)
  - Michigan Rag Co., Grand Haven, Mich
    - Clothing for fun. circa 1993 (Box 8)
    - [Catalog] fall/winter 1993 (Box 8)
  - Miles' Drug Store, Dexter, Mich
    - Catalogue of perfect fitting patterns from the Universal Fashion Co. [cat for autumn-winter 1885/86] (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous clothing and dress companies
    - Fashion plates from Godey's Lady Magazine September 1866, November 1866 (Box 8)
    - Mounted clipping "Way Back When in Washtenaw," showing photo of small girl fashionably dressed [from Huron Valley Ad-Visor January 10, 1968] (Box 8)
  - Newcomb, Endicott and Co., Detroit, Mich
    - Catalogue, Spring-Summer 1905, [women's clothing] (Box 8)
    - Handkerchief and other Christmas suggestions circa 1919 (Box 8)
    - Magazine of Fashion, Fall-Winter 1918-1919 [Women's clothing] (Box 8)
    - Magazine of Fashion, Fall-Winter 1920/21, [Women's clothing] (Box 8)
    - Magazine of fashion, spring-summer 1913, [women's and children's clothing] (Box 8)
    - Magazine of Fashion, Spring-Summer 1917, [Women's clothing] (Box 8)
    - Magazine of Fashion, Spring-Summer 1919, [Women's clothing] (Box 8)
    - Magazine of Fashion, Undermuslin 1917, [Women's clothing] (Box 8)
    - Our summer number 1917 (Box 8)
    - Our summer number 1919 (Box 8)
    - Our summer number 1920 (Box 8)
  - Opperman Fur Co., Saginaw, Mich
    - Furs of quality, 1865 1915. Golden Jubilee: fifty years in Saginaw. (Box 8)
      [Contains a brief history of the Co. and services it provides]
  - Pingree & Smith, Detroit, Mich
    - Folded leaflet advertising "kid" shoes, sold by H. W. Portland, Mich. circa 1885 (Box 8)